so now that we have seen what the
performance looks like when we refuse to
make any predictions let's see what the
performance is with the so-called not
taken prediction which amounts to Simply
fetching the next instruction as if none
of the instructions was a taken Branch
when we refuse to predict anything a
branch every Branch would cost us three
cycles and even a non Branch instruction
would cost us two cycles even in a
relatively shallow five- stage pipeline
when we predict that the instruction we
are fetching is not a taken Branch we
get that branches now cost us one or
three Cycles one cycle for not taken
Branch three cycles for a taken branch
and a non Branch instruction always cost
us one cycle because in that case the
not taken prediction is always correct
so as we can see the predict not taken
always wins over refusing to predict for
non- branches we are always one cycle
better for branches we are either the
same or two cycles better this is why
every processor that has a pipeline will
do some Branch prediction even if the
prediction it is doing is simply
increment the PC and fetch the next
instruction note that that type of
prediction is really cheap all you have
to do is increment the PC you don't
actually have to know anything about
branches or other instructions so it's
very easy to do it you have to be able
to increment the PC anyway